RG 026, Division of Special Revenue
Connecticut State Library
Division of Special Revenue records
1971-2011
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Division of Special Revenue
24.25 cubic feet
The Division of Special Revenue ensures the highest degree of integrity in the conduct of all forms of legalized gambling within the State of Connecticut and the federally recognized Tribal Nations within the State. The Division of Special Revenues accomplishes this by licensing or permitting all individuals and entities that are involved with legalized gambling and by monitoring and educating to ensure compliance with the gaming laws and the Tribal-State agreements.
RG026
2012-053, 2012-054, T000544
Historical Note
The Commission on Special Revenue was established on July 1, 1971, and was formally organized on October 12, 1971. The Commission initiated and administered the Connecticut State Lottery. On July 1, 1979, the Commission was replaced by the Gaming Policy Board and the Division of Special Revenue within the Department of Business Regulation. On July 1, 1980, the Board and Division began operating under the Department of Revenue Services for administrative purposes only, following the abolition of the Department of Business Regulation. In 1996, the Connecticut State Lottery component of the Division of Special Revenue becomes a quasi-public corporation and the name changed to the Connecticut Lottery Coporation. In the late 1990s, the State transferred administration of the lottery to the Connecticut Lottery Corporation. The Division supports activities of the Gaming Policy Board and both regulate the conduct of legalized gambling within the state and monitor compliance with Tribal-State Compacts.
See also the.
Scope and Content
Commission on Special Revenue and Gaming Policy Board meeting minutes, 1971-2005, and recordings, 1979-2011; hearing decisions, 1984-2010; and sample lottery tickets, 1972-1974.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Alternate Authores:
Connecticut. Commission of Special Revenue; Connecticut. Gaming Policy Board
Subjects:
Connecticut. Gaming Policy Board -- Records and Correspondence; Gambling -- Connecticut; Lotteries -- Connecticut; Lottery Tickets
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
Accession T000544 was transferred to the State Library in 1974. Accessions 2012-053 and 2012-054 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on June 28, 2012.
Container List
- Series 1. Gaming Policy Board, 1971-2011; 2012-053
  Minutes prior to July 1, 1979 are for Commission on Special Revenue.
  Minutes for 1988-1991 were note transferred to the Connecticut State Library.
  Meeting recordings, 1979 - 2007 November 1 are on audio cassette. Meeting recordings, 2007 December 19 - 2001 were created as .trm files and are on CD. TRM files are audio files created by FTR (ForTheRecord) digital courtroom recording software saved in a proprietary format but could be played with TheRecordPlayer, a free TRM player provided by ForTheRecord.
  - Minutes, 1971 October 12 - 1975 November 19 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1975 November 25 - 1977 October 26 (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1977 November 2 - 1979 May 30 (Box 3)
  - Minutes, 1979 June 13 - 1987 December 29 (Box 4)
  - Minutes, 1992 January 16 - 2005 November 22 (Box 5)
  - Minutes, 1979 August 2 - 1982 May 27 (Box 6)
    These are duplicates.
  - Resolutions, 1971-1979 (Box 6)
  - Executive session minutes, 1975 October 1 - 1976 December 31, 1978 January 4 - 1979 June 20 (Box 6)
  - Meeting recordings, 1979-1992 (Box 7)
  - Meeting recordings, 1993-2011 (Box 8)
- Series 2. Hearing Decisions, 1984-2010; 2012-054
  - Hearing decisions, 1984 February 23 - 1985 August 5 (Box 1)
  - Hearing decisions, 1985 July 25 - 1986 June 30 (Box 1)
  - Decisions rendered, 1986 July 1 - 1987 June 30 (Box 1)
  - Decisions rendered, 1987 July 1 - 1988 June 30 (Box 1)
  - Decisions rendered, 1988 July 1 - 1989 June 30 (Box 1)
  - Decisions rendered, 1989 July 1 - 1990 June 30 (Box 1)
  - Lottery, 1990 July 1 - 1991 June 30 (Box 1)
  - Charitable games, gambling regulations, off-track betting, patron reinstatement, 1990 July 1 - 1991 June 30 (Box 1)
  - Lottery, 1991 July 1 - 1991 June 30 (Box 2)
  - Charitable games, gambling regulations, Indian gaming, patron reinstatement, 1991 July 1 - 1992 June 30 (Box 2)
  - Lottery, 1992 July 1 - 1993 June 30 (Box 2)
  - Charitable games, gambling regulations, Indian gaming, patron reinstatement, 1992 July 1 - 1993 June 30 (Box 2)
  - Lottery, 1993 July 1 - 1994 June 30 (Box 3)
  - Charitable games, gambline regulations - Plainfield Greyhoound Track, gambling regulations - jai alai, off-track betting - patron reinstatement, jai alai - patron reinstatement, 1994 July 1 - 1996 June 30 (Box 3)
  - Foxwoods Casino, 1993 July 1 - 1994 June 30 (Box 3)
  - Lottery, 1994 July 1 - 1995 June 30 (Box 4)
  - Charitable games, gaming regulations - jai ali, gaming regulations - Plainfield Greyhound Park, off-track betting - patron reinstatement, 1994 July 1 - 1995 June 30 (Box 4)
  - Foxwoods Casino, 1994 July 1 - 1995 June 30 (Box 4)
  - Lottery, 1995 July 1 - 1996 June 30 (Box 4)
  - Foxwoods Casino, 1995 July 1 - 1996 June 30 (Box 5)
  - Charitable games, off-track betting patron reinstatement, gaming regulations - jai alai, ogg-track betting, gaming regulations - Plainfield Greyhound Park, 1995 July 1 - 1996 June 30 (Box 5)
  - Lottery, 1996 July 1 - 1997 June 30 (Box 5)
  - Foxwoods Casino, 1996 July 1 - 1997 June 30 (Box 5)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, 1996 July 1 - 1997 June 30 (Box 5)
  - Charitable games, off-track betting patron reinstatement, off-track betting, jai alai - patron reinstatement, gaming regulations - Plainfield Training Park, 1996 July 1 - 1997 June 30 (Box 6)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, A-M, 1997 July 1 - 1998 June 30 (Box 6)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, N-Z, 1997 July 1 - 1998 June 30 (Box 6)
  - Lottery, 1997 July 1 - 1998 June 30 (Box 6)
  - Foxwoods Casino, 1997 July 1 - 1998 June 30 (Box 6)
  - Charitable games, off-track betting, off-track betting patron reinstatement, jai alai, jai alai - patron reinstatemen, Plainfield Greyhound Park, 1997 July 1 - 1998 June 30 (Box 6)
  - Charitable games, off-track betting, off-track betting patron reinstatement, gaming regulations - jai alai, jai alai - patron reinstatement, Plainfield Greyhound Park, 1998 July 1 - 1999 June 30 (Box 7)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, A-Z, 1998 July 1 - 1999 June 30 (Box 7)
  - Lottery, A-D, 1998 July 1 - 1999 June 30 (Box 7)
  - Lottery, E-Q, 1998 July 1 - 1999 June 30 (Box 7)
  - Lottery, R-Z, 1998 July 1 - 1999 June 30 (Box 7)
  - Foxwoods Casino, A-K, 1998 July 1 - 1999 June 30 (Box 7)
  - Foxwoods Casino, L-Z, 1998 July 1 - 1999 June 30 (Box 7)
  - Lottery, A-F, 1999 July 1 - 2000 June 30 (Box 8)
  - Lottery, G-P, 1999 July 1 - 2000 June 30 (Box 8)
  - Lottery, Q-Z, 1999 July 1 - 2000 June 30 (Box 8)
  - Foxwoods Casino, A-M, 1999 July 1 - 2000 June 30 (Box 8)
  - Foxwoods Casino, N-Z, 1999 July 1 - 2000 June 30 (Box 8)
  - Off-track betting, off-track betting patron reinstatement, Bridgeport/Plainfield Greyhound Tracks, gaming regulation - jai alai, charitable games, 1999 July 1 - 2000 June 30 (Box 8)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, A-M, 1999 July 1 - 2000 June 30 (Box 8)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, N-Z, 1999 July 1 - 2000 June 30 (Box 8)
  - Lottery, A-F, 2000 July 1 - 2001 June 30 (Box 9)
  - Lottery, G-P, 2000 July 1 - 2001 June 30 (Box 9)
  - Lottery, Q-Z, 2000 July 1 - 2001 June 30 (Box 9)
  - Off-track betting, off-track betting patron reinstatement, Bridgeport/Plainfield Greyhound Parks, gaming regulations, jai alai, charitable games, 2000 July 1 - 2001 June 30 (Box 9)
  - Foxwoods Casino, A-M, 2000 July 1 - 2001 June 30 (Box 9)
  - Foxwoods Casino, 2000 July 1 - 2001 June 30 (Box 9)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, A-M, 2000 July 1 - 2001 June 30 (Box 9)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, N-Z, 2000 July 1 - 2001 June 30 (Box 9)
  - Lottery, A-F, 2001 July 1 - 2002 June 30 (Box 9)
  - Lottrery, G-P, 2001 July 1 - 2002 June 30 (Box 9)
  - Lottery, Q-Z, 2001 July 1 - 2002 June 30 (Box 10)
  - Foxwoods Casino, A-M, 2001 July 1 - 2002 June 30 (Box 10)
  - Foxwoods Casino, N-Z, 2001 July 1 - 2002 June 30 (Box 10)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, A-M, 2001 July 1 - 2002 June 30 (Box 10)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, N-Z, 2001 July 1 - 2002 June 30 (Box 10)
  - Off-track betting, off-track betting patron reinstatement, Bridgeport/Plainfield Geyhound Parks, charitable games, 2001 July 1 - 2002 June 30 (Box 10)
  - Lottery, A-F, 2002 July 1 - 2003 June 30 (Box 10)
  - Lottery, G-P, 2002 July 1 - 2003 June 30 (Box 10)
  - Lottery, Q-Z, 2002 July 1 - 2003 June 30 (Box 10)
  - Foxwoods Casino, A-M, 2002 July 1 - 2003 June 30 (Box 10)
  - Foxwoods Casino, N-Z, 2002 July 1 - 2003 June 30 (Box 10)
  - Mohgan Sun, A-M, 2002 July 1 - 2003 June 30 (Box 11)
  - Mohegan Subm N-Z, 2002 July 1 - 2003 June 30 (Box 11)
  - Off-track betting, off-track betting patron reinstatement, gamine regulations jai alai, charitable games, 2002 July 1 - 2003 June 30 (Box 11)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, 2003 July 1 - 2004 June 30 (Box 11)
  - Charitable games, 2003 July 1 - 2004 June 30 (Box 11)
  - Lottery, 2003 July 1 - 2004 June 30 (Box 11)
  - Foxwoods Casino, 2003 July 1 - 2004 June 30 (Box 11)
  - Lottery, 2004 July 1 - 2005 June 30 (Box 11)
  - Foxxwoods Casino, 2004 July 1 - 2005 June 30 (Box 12)
  - Mohegan Sub, 2004 July 1 - 2005 June 30 (Box 12)
  - Charitable games, 2004 July 1 - 2005 June 30 (Box 12)
  - Charitable games, Plainfield Greyhound Park, Shoreline Star Greyhound Park, 2005 July 1 - 2006 June 30 (Box 12)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, 2005 July 1 - 2006 June 30 (Box 12)
  - Lottery, A-M, 2005 July 1 - 2006 June 30 (Box 12)
  - Lottery, N-Z, 2005 July 1 - 2006 June 30 (Box 12)
  - Foxwoods Casino, 2005 July 1 - 2006 June 30 (Box 12)
  - Lottery, 2006 July 1 - 2007 June 30 (Box 12)
  - Foxwoods Casino, 2006 July 1 - 2007 June 30 (Box 12)
  - Charitable games, 2006 July 1 - 2007 June 30 (Box 12)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, 2006 July 1 - 2007 June 30 (Box 12)
  - Charitable games, off-track betting, patron reinstatement, 2007 July 1 - 2008 June 30 (Box 13)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, 2007 July 1 - 2008 June 30 (Box 13)
  - Foxwoods Casino, 2007 July 1 - 2008 June 30 (Box 13)
  - Lottery, A-M, 2007 July 1 - 2008 June 30 (Box 13)
  - Lottery, N-Z, 2007 July 1 - 2008 June 30 (Box 13)
  - Lottery, A-M, 2008 July 1 - 2009 June 30 (Box 13)
  - Lottery, N-Z, 2008 July 1 - 2009 June 30 (Box 13)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, 2008 July 1 - 2009 June 30 (Box 14)
  - Foxwoods Casino, 2008 July 1 - 2009 June 30 (Box 14)
  - Charitable games, off-track betting, patron reinstatement, 2008 July 1 - 2009 June 30 (Box 14)
  - Mohegan Sun Casino, 2009 July 1 - 2010 June 30 (Box 14)
  - Foxwoods Casino, 2009 July 1 - 2010 June 30 (Box 14)
  - Charitable games, off-track betting, patron reinstatement, 2009 July 1 - 2010 June 30 (Box 14)
  - Lottery, A-M, 2009 July 1 - 2010 June 30 (Box 14)
  - Lottery, N-Z, 2009 July 1 - 2010 June 30 (Box 14)
  - Anthony J. Pellulo hearing decision, 2003 January 23 (Box 15-16)
- Series 3. Sample Lottery Tickets, 1972-1974; T000544
  - Sample lottery tickets, 1972-1974; 1 inch (Box 1)